Harsha Vykunta

Seattle, Washington 98121 • 469.974.7885 • harshavardhan.biit@gmail.com • LinkedIn • Portfolio

QUALIFICATIONS PROFILE

Enthusiastic and inventive with interrelated education, innovation, and experience to contribute to long-range operational goals in a **Full-Stack Developer** role. Aptitude for rapidly acquiring new information, procedures, and technologies. Remarkably organized with ability to multitask. Excellent customer, engineer, management, and staff communications. Capable of matching business objectives to existing and developing technologies.

Core Technologies:

Languages: Java (1.8), JavaScript (Es6), Python

Databases: SQL Server, PostreSQL, MongoDB

Applications: Node.js, React.js, Express, Django, Angular, Redux

Other: HTML 5, CSS 3, JIRA, Git, Docker, Trello, Webpack, AWS

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Master of Science in Information Systems – (2019)

Northeastern University, Seattle, Washington

Bachelor of Technology in Metallurgical and Materials Engineering – (2016)

National Institute of Technology, Rourkela, Odisha, India

EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS

Hoonuit, Minneapolis, Minnesota

Software Engineer Intern, 8/2018 – 12/2018

Technologies: Python, Django, TypeScript, Angular, AWS, HTML, CSS, Karma, and Jasmine

Collaborate on forthcoming development consultations and product design with multifunctional teams including; business clients, data scientists, engineers, and project managers in order to construct company platforms. Originate, plan, implement, and maintain innovative and existing features of our SaaS-platform.

- Generate Docker containers for exclusive development and production environments.
- Developed Assignment creation and survey features.
- Integrated Credly's badging service to provide badges for the pathways.

Northeastern University, Seattle, Washington

Teaching Assistant for INFO 6350: Smartphones-Based Web Development, 1/2019 – 4/2019.

Teaching Assistant for INFO 6205: Program Structures and Algorithms, 1/2018 – 4/2018.

Teaching Assistant for INFO 5100: Application Engineering and Development, 9/2017 - 12/2017.

Provided instructional support to university professors in busy lab-based environment. Assisted students in

the numerous design frameworks. Established course logistics and guided student code reviews and program tests. Facilitated solutions related to course issues for students.

Harsha Vykunta

Page Two

- Guided students through Java, Swift, IOS Development, Data structures and Algorithms.
- Utilized Git to track changes in student's repositories and submit to faculty for review and grading.

PROJECTS

Experiential Project | Owlz.io (project-demo)

Technologies: PostgreSQL, Java, JavaScript, Spring, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, Git and Heroku

An Experiential Project organized by Northeastern University and Seattle based Startup Owlz.io. Utilized cutting-edge knowledge of progressive web apps and development strategies. Accomplished website implementation and maintenance on Heroku. Utilized JIRA as bug tracking/program management tool.

 Achieved an 80% reduction in website load times and build sizes by means of asynchronous loading for react components.

Social Networking Application (project-demo)

Technologies: MongoDB, Node.js, React, Redux, Express, HTML, CSS, Git and Heroku

Inspired by Twitter. Rather than the chronological news feed that Twitter provides today, the news feed is based on a ranking system that ranks the user's interaction and his/her following.

Utilized Twitter's OAuth authentication and RESTful APIs to share posts on twitter.

E-commerce Application (project-demo)

Technologies: PostgreSQL, Python, Django, jQuery, Ajax, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Git and Heroku

The application provides persisting cart management for both Authenticated and Guest users, suggests based on previous purchases.

- Utilized Stripe's APIs for payment option management and MailChimp's APIs for marketing emails.
- The application is hosted on Heroku and uses AWS's S3 for serving static files and images.

AWARD

Teaching Excellence – 2017-2018 (Academic Year)Northeastern University, Seattle, Washington